A Guide to the Virginia 4-H Horse Program Records, ca. 1959-2002, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia 4-H Horse Program Records, ca. 1959-2002, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 26/4/2
4 Cubic Feet; 4 boxes
The Virginia 4-H Horse Program Records, RG 26/4/2, include photographs, slides, negatives, and audiotapes from Virginia 4-H State Shows, State Fairs, and other events throughout the state. 4-H programs began in Virginia in 1908, and since then, the Virginia Cooperative Extension, Virginia Tech, and Virginia State University have hosted the Virginia 4-H Horse Program, which emphasizes equine selection, nutrition, management, riding, and horsemanship.
Virginia Cooperative Extension. 4-H Youth Development
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia 4-H Program Records Collection was donated to Special Collections in June 2017.
Historical Note
4-H started in Illinois in 1898 and came to Virginia in 1908. The program was originally known as Agriculture and Home Economics Clubs before becoming 4-H Clubs. Today, 4-H can be found in 107 counties and cities of Virginia. 4-H Clubs, specifically the Horse Programs, provide physical and emotional development, including confidence building. The Virginia Cooperative Extension, Virginia Tech, and Virginia State University host the Virginia 4-H Horse Program, which emphasizes equine selection, nutrition, management, riding, and horsemanship. The program hosts horse camps, state shows, educational events, and more throughout the state.
Scope and Content
The Virginia 4-H Horse Program Records contain photographs, audiotapes, negatives, and slides, which document state shows, Virginia State Fairs, and other events throughout the state. Slides, dating from 1959 to 1993, include pictures of horses, 4-H teams, 4-H competitions and events, and informational slides. Photographs depict the 2002 and 2003 State Horse Shows, Awards Programs, the 1996 Judging Team, the 1991 Virginia State Fair, and the 1973 State 4-H Horse Show. There are also assorted and undated negatives and photographs from Smithfield, regional competitions, State Horse Shows, and State Fairs. Finally, the collection contains undated audiotapes of several individuals and judging teams.
Arrangement
The Virginia 4-H Program Records are organized by type: Slides, Photographs, Negatives, and Audiotapes.
Index Terms
Subjects:
4-H clubs; Virginia Cooperative Extension Service; University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Cooperative Extension. 4-H Youth Development; Virginia 4-H Horse Program
Contents List
- Slides, ca. 1959-1993, undated
  - Slides, 1959-1977 (Box 1)
  - Slides, 1980-1993 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Horse Industry Original Slides, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Photographs, ca. 1973-2002, undated
  - State Horse Show at Virginia Horse Show in Lexington Photographs, Sept. 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Awards Program Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Educational Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Judging Team Photographs and Newspaper Article, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1973 State 4-H Horse Show Photographs, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Smithfield Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - State Fair Photographs, 1991-09 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Southern Regionals Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Horse Center Lexington and State Horse Show Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - State Fair of VA - 4-H Horse Show Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Negatives, undated
  - Assorted Negatives and Envelopes, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Audiotapes, undated
  - Carolyn Rice, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Kelly "The Machine" Pitts, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Jessica Artrip, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Micah Pue Horse Judging Cans, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)